<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Shermans's Notes</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Shermans's Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://shermanrose.uk/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>shermanrose.uk</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/shermanrose.uk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/shermanrose.uk/</guid><description>Previous Websites I&amp;rsquo;ve made and trashed many personal websites over the years. They all started as somewhere to blog, take notes and showcase projects. And rather than get on with it, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been distracted by the looks, or the function, or the hosting.
It is then no surprise then that over the years I have very little to show for it. Most of the older sites have been lost to failed hard drives or expired and forgotten about hosting.</description></item><item><title>Numbers Game</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/numbers_game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/numbers_game/</guid><description>Numbers is small game, where you attempt to reach the target number by adding or subtracing a combination of numbers to reach it.
Here is a gif showing selection and deselction of tiles, as well as selection incorrect ones. Here is another gif showing aceptting a selection</description></item><item><title>Bytemark Dashboards</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/bytemark-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/bytemark-dashboards/</guid><description>Bytemark Dashboards was a side project to my Customer Support work, to make some information screens to help with properly managing the support queues and jobs that needed to be done.
Originally I had stumbled on a piece of software called Dashing. Dashing, whilst not longer maintained by the original creators, has a lovely out of the box set of widgets that show basic numbers and graphs, constantly updated with Server Sent Events (SSE).</description></item><item><title>Japanese Trainer</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/japanese-trainer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/japanese-trainer/</guid><description>I took a couple of Japanese modules at university and I happen to like programming. So I decided to help myself out and write a Flash game to help me learn!
Written using Adobe Flash and ActionScript 3, this small program will take you through a quiz of Hiragana and Katakana with the parameters you define.
If you still have flash installed have a go! There are some more screen shots below otherwise!</description></item><item><title>Learning Programming Through Competition</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/learning-programming-through-competition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/learning-programming-through-competition/</guid><description>LPTC f, or short, was my final year university project. The project spec was to create an application to aid new learners in procedural based programming by having them compete for their code.
The application was written in Java and comprised of two parts.
The first was a simple text editor that could compile java byte-code at run-time. The second was a 2D arena based game where the compiled byte-code from multiple users was run.</description></item></channel></rss>