<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ruby on Shermans's Notes</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/tags/ruby/</link><description>Recent content in ruby on Shermans's Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://shermanrose.uk/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bytemark Dashboards</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/bytemark-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/bytemark-dashboards/</guid><description>Bytemark Dashboards was a side project to my Customer Support work, to make some information screens to help with properly managing the support queues and jobs that needed to be done.
Originally I had stumbled on a piece of software called Dashing. Dashing, whilst not longer maintained by the original creators, has a lovely out of the box set of widgets that show basic numbers and graphs, constantly updated with Server Sent Events (SSE).</description></item><item><title>JRuby is making my VIM startup unbearable</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/jruby-is-making-my-vim-startup-unbareable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/jruby-is-making-my-vim-startup-unbareable/</guid><description>TLDR: If you use vim-ruby and jruby you&amp;rsquo;re going to have a bad time. 2.5~ seconds to open or save a file kinda bad time. If you want to have your code properly checked on the version of ruby you are working with, tough. Other wise you can add let g:ruby_path in your .vimrc to configure which ruby build you use. Remember that rvm can change your ruby automatically. so be careful.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Rails 5 self hosted fonts</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/setting-up-font-awesome-and-rails/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/setting-up-font-awesome-and-rails/</guid><description>TL-DR; Get to the point
I just started another small side project based on a fresh rails 5 setup.
I thought this was a good opportunity to try out a different CSS framework called Bulma, which I saw mentioned on Garry&amp;rsquo;s Blog. Why not? Small projects are great for trying new things.
bulma uses font-awesome but does not package it in their framework, which is fair. They suggest that you use a CDN copy of font-awesome.</description></item><item><title>Talk To Me - A 'Simple' Side Project</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/talk-to-me-a-simple-side-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/talk-to-me-a-simple-side-project/</guid><description>I have a 3 year old nephew, who loves comptuers, and why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t he? They are everywhere. I can remember the first time I saw anything like a computer. I have memories of playing the NES at the age of 2.
So as his very mature and responsible uncle, it is my duty to guide his journey in the devices that are shaping our entire lives. Since I have studied and practiced computing for more years than I like to think about, especially when considering how inept I am, I think it is important for him to know what to can do for and to him.</description></item></channel></rss>