<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes from 2020 on Shermans's Notes</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/</link><description>Recent content in Notes from 2020 on Shermans's Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-11th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-11th-2020/</guid><description>Universal links in ios https://developer.apple.com/documentation/safariservices/supporting_associated_domains_in_your_app?language=objc Important to note the change of the schema in iOS 13, as well as the change of location for the file. However there is no schema version in the document so it becomes a case of managing endpoints Also the json itself has variable keys, something I think that should be avoided like the plague as it make parsing code of the document a lot more fraught, and more difficult in something strongly typed like java In the end as we are only reading a base file, we can get away with typing the &amp;ldquo;routes&amp;rdquo; part of the schema as a JsonElement to preserve the keys during deserialisation, however under different circumstances&amp;hellip; sysdiagnose Apparently a system level tool that collects data ( including #AASA data apprently) Best way to trigger it now is to assign a single tap Assistive Touch button on the phone that is bound to Analytics.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-13th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-13th-2020/</guid><description> #unity https://docs.unity3d.com/Packages/com.unity.device-simulator@2.0/manual/index.html Preview packaged for better developing for a mobile by simulating the frame Replaces the usual play mode viewer in the editor</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-25th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-25th-2020/</guid><description>data_structures Checking membership of a large set quickly! Using hashes to set bits in a #bit_vector in order to test if an element may be in a set. This could be used as a filter for more expensive tests to hone down on a positive data set. some of the three filters can be tuned and dialed in for performance / memory constraints and to fit certain data sets.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-26th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-26th-2020/</guid><description>kotlin Including Kotlin in to an existing project
https://kotlinlang.org/docs/reference/using-gradle.html#plugin-and-versions Add the gradle-kotlin plugin, add a source set config Kotlin through #gradle seems to work with their instructions with no issue IDE Support #vscode There is a Kotlin plugin, however current it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support using java in Kotlin https://github.com/fwcd/kotlin-language-server/issues/192 this is a must for interop programming Errors about unresolved classes for the java stdlib (e.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-27th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-27th-2020/</guid><description> kotlinjava #Testing #JUnit5 Testing work just as you think it would. The interop is real! Extended our base test classes and everything #GSON Works as expected with data classes. no issues at all #Data Structures#lonely-integer-xor-integer-pairs#Papers #Bloom Filters are point based filters For range queries : ARF - Adaptive Range Filter http://www.vldb.org/pvldb/vol6/p1714-kossmann.pdf Hierarchical Bloom Filters https://arxiv.org/abs/1712.04544</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-5th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-5th-2020/</guid><description>FaceBook API Dev otes #Facebook #API #Marketing
Running Ads on the FB network is a thing&amp;hellip;
#Deeplinks allow you to have a target for inside of an app as long as you have a provider links myapp:// registered on the phone OS
However in order to be even allowed to set it up FB require you to embed their SDK in your app first&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-8th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/february-8th-2020/</guid><description>#facebook-unity-sdk Adding #facebook-unity-sdk to a unity app has been a pain Import the package was trivial at first however, the menu it adds would not work for some reason at first. Making the build process for IOS work after the fact was also a pain in the ass Firstly it uses CocoaPods an app / xCode package manager in order to pull the underlying facebook-ios-sdk packages down however that in it self was not enough to get things godoing Had to install CocoaPods using brew Ensure that the project includes a subproject for the pods in xCode which if you pods installation is missing can happen after a bit of brew link that went away after getting unity to rebuild the ios poroject The package uses clang modules so that had to be enabled as a build option This could be done in xCode however we have a post processing script of as part of the unity build process for the xCode project, (Helpful to look at unity cloud build resources here) and it&amp;rsquo;s better off living there for reproducible builds.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/feburary-2nd-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/feburary-2nd-2020/</guid><description>#Software Engineering Engineerring-belieifs What do I believe? https://about.wtf.studio/mondays/ #Creativity #Work java #errors Really interesting failure. If the JVM fails to init a class once, it will complain, and 16:53:58 Caused by: java.lang.ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException: Index 2 out of bounds for length 2a t starship.mvr.model.NotifyType.&amp;lt;clinit&amp;gt;(NotifyType.java:90) ... 9 common frames omitted Caused by: java.lang.ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException: Index 2 out of bounds for length 2at starship.mvr.model.NotifyType.&amp;lt;clinit&amp;gt;(NotifyType.java:90) ... 9 common frames omitted 16:54:001.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-21st-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-21st-2020/</guid><description>Java Executor pools private static final int NUM_THREADS = 4;private final Logger log = Logger.getLogger(getClass()); private LinkedBlockingQueue&amp;lt; Runnable&amp;gt; taskQueue = new LinkedBlockingQueue&amp;lt; Runnable&amp;gt;();private List&amp;lt; Runnable&amp;gt; running = Collections.synchronizedList(new ArrayList()); public void doSomeStuffConcurrently() { Executor executor = new ThreadPoolExecutor(NUM_THREADS, NUM_THREADS, 0L, TimeUnit.MILLISECONDS, taskQueue, Executors.defaultThreadFactory()) { @Override protected &amp;lt; T&amp;gt; RunnableFuture&amp;lt; T&amp;gt; newTaskFor(final Runnable runnable, T value) { return new FutureTask&amp;lt; T&amp;gt;(runnable, value) { @Override public String toString() { return runnable.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-22nd-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-22nd-2020/</guid><description> http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg21/docs/papers/2020/p2028r0.pdf #Paper about #ABI format concerns when making changes to to the cpp stdlib. Quite good at explaining issues around ABI concerns and issues</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-23rd-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-23rd-2020/</guid><description>#self_improvment Why Procrastination is about managing emotions, not time https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20200121-why-procrastination-is-about-managing-emotions-not-time Web of Documents vs Web of Applications http://blog.danieljanus.pl/2019/10/07/web-of-documents/ HTTP https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2019/03/12/looking-for-the-refresh-header/ The refresh header never existed! java Building jars is still fun&amp;hellip; even better with [[Gradle]] Though it is possible to get a nice config with a great manifest file task createServerAppJar(type: ShadowJar) { group &amp;#34;vTime&amp;#34; description &amp;#34;Create a .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-24th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-24th-2020/</guid><description>java When creating a fat Jar care needs to be taken with any singed .jars Firstly if there are any signatures in META-INF the Jar will not run due to security failures Second if if you exclude the signing files, signed jars will not be loaded at run time due to failing the security check You can exclude the files like so task createServerAppJar(type: ShadowJar) { classifier = &amp;#34;server&amp;#34; from sourceSets.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-25th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-25th-2020/</guid><description>#vscode Focusing terminal keyboard shortcut https://github.com/Microsoft/vscode/issues/12054 In Keyboard shortcuts: workbench.action.terminal.focus [ctrl] + [shift] + # workbench.action.focusActiveEditorGroup [ctrl] + [shift] + # when terminalFocus This makes a switchable key from terminal to editor #Gradle Jar building + multi sourceset configuration Below is an example of using the class path of another source set when defining a new one, you could also use toolsImplementation sourceSets.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-27th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-27th-2020/</guid><description> Reddison https://github.com/redisson/redisson Very interesting Redis library consider in next project Docker is the dangerous gamble which we will regret http://archive.is/zkmaE Very interesting read and style but very long</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-29th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-29th-2020/</guid><description>https://github.com/Siderite/LInQer LINQ implementation in JS Bug in AWS java SDK Bug in our code where requests would timeout. Seems that threads where hanging / locking in the pool that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have access to. after a log of head scratching, it was suggested to check if it really is a bug in their code. Out but seemed similar to this one which was fixed. https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-java/issues/2089 The take home point is: &amp;ldquo;The time taken to bump a version vs trying to find a problem in our code&amp;rdquo; Even if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the fix (Though there is a high chance it is) I would have spent a lot longer not getting any further in finding out why than to bump and see what happens next.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-31st-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/january-31st-2020/</guid><description> #math #graphics https://marctenbosch.com/quaternions Why Quarterions are a complication of Rotors, or Why I should learn Geometric Algebra</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/july-21st-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/july-21st-2020/</guid><description>#windows #AD #GPO Domain Group Policy Management Running gpmgnt.msc will give you a local editor. Instead run Group Policy Management on the Domain Controller itself Nagivate to Group Policy Objects from Forests / Domains / domain.local Right click the policy / or create new to open a copy of the group policy editor that is connected to the domain. You will know this as it will show [DOMAIN.LOCAL] Policy in the policy title.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/march-12th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/march-12th-2020/</guid><description> kotlin https://www.kotlinresources.com/library/kotson/ DSL in Kotlin for #GSON #Patterns #Design Railroad Oriented Programming https://fsharpforfunandprofit.com/rop/ F# examples and slides included Example implementation in kotlin https://medium.com/@its_damo/error-handling-in-kotlin-a07c2ee0e06f</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/march-13th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/march-13th-2020/</guid><description> java http://homepages.inf.ed.ac.uk/wadler/gj/Documents/gj-oopsla.pdf Making the future safe for the past :Adding Genericity to the JavaTM Programming Language #music, #audio #GameDev https://www.audiokinetic.com/products/wwise/ Talking to Matt it sounds like this is the engine that makes the sounds in games such as Mini Metro and Mini Motorways work.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/march-16th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2020/march-16th-2020/</guid><description> java Something to watch out for in future when trying to get the parameterized type from a class, i.e the SomeOtherClass from Class&amp;lt;SomeOtherClass&amp;gt; Getting the type is easy, especially if you only have one type: public Type getType() { return ((ParameterizedType) getClass() .getGenericSuperclass()).getActualTypeArguments()[0]; } Watch out for calling Type.getClass() as you will not get the class you were expecting, but the class that represents the instance of the Type class Type itself is an interfaces that Class implements, so it should be OK to pass the type instance to places you would pass classes</description></item></channel></rss>