<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes from 2021 on Shermans's Notes</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/</link><description>Recent content in Notes from 2021 on Shermans's Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-16th-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-16th-2021/</guid><description> Todo Today I learned (Notes) 50-game-camera-mistakes - A great watch! Epic use a modified Doxygen for unreal https://answers.unrealengine.com/questions/77297/what-tool-does-epic-use-for-generating-api-documen.html Doxygen hope pages for sepcial coments commands https://www.doxygen.nl/manual/commands.html#cmdsa Tomorow&amp;rsquo;s Tasks</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-19th-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-19th-2021/</guid><description>Todo Continue work on Camera Manager Implementation Today I learned (Notes) Abstract Classes in #cpp Abstract classes in #cpp are a bit more implicit than other languages https://en.cppreference.com/w/cpp/language/abstract_class A class / struct becomes abstract when it has a virtual member that is = 0 making it a pure virtual. Any calls to this should fail at runtime. Example from the above link: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 struct Base { virtual int g(); virtual ~Base() {} }; struct A : Base { // OK: declares three member virtual functions, two of them pure virtual int f() \= 0, g() override \= 0, h(); // OK: destructor can be pure too ~A() \= 0; // Error: pure-specifier on a function definition virtual int b()\=0 {} }; Camera Control in #unreal Understood a bit more about how the camera manager framework is put together.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-23rd-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-23rd-2021/</guid><description>Todo Single camera via camera manager in UE4 Today I learned (Notes) ue-editor
Having custom editor only objects appear is quite a task overall
CameraComponent is a good example of how it is done in source code: Engine\UE4\Source\Runtime\Engine\Classes\Camera\CameraComponent.h : 149. This header contains the editor driven functions for creating an managing the proxy mesh that represents the camera positioning in the Blueprint Editor. Powered by a ProxyMeshComponent, it is updated when OnRegister is called.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-8th-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-8th-2021/</guid><description>Todo ~Investigate mouse capture in unreal~ Investigate missing audio in packaged game Today I learned (Notes) ue-packaging If a file isn&amp;rsquo;t directly reference in editor it will be excludedin cooks / packaged builds. You need to add the directory to the Additonal Asset Directories to Cook array in the Project Settings -&amp;gt; Packaging menu under advanced ue-project-launcher Useful tool to build and deploy the project to a specific device. Advanced mode gives great control over config Variant *NoEditor, Config Development and Data build ByTheBook is a good way to get in editor logging of the entire build process but also logs in realtime of what is happening in game.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/feburary-4th-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/feburary-4th-2021/</guid><description>js JS Promise chaining: https://javascript.info/promise-chaining # Promises
#javascript #promises
Promise Chaining JS Promise chaining So it&amp;rsquo;s a little tricky but kinda simple. A then that returns a value, registers a handler that is run after the main promise is resolved. All then that return values like this get the same result A then that rejects or throws calls the first catch handler on all in the promise, defined by order, because JS&amp;hellip; So it&amp;rsquo;s a little tricky but kinda simple.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/july-18th-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/july-18th-2021/</guid><description> Todo Today I learned (Notes) #VSCode #golang Had issues with multiple modes in a single workspace. Turns out the language server gopls does currently suppport this by default. Casues a lot of import errors, which disables the server pretty much until resolved. While the fix has been in for a while,it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have become the default. To enable experimental support add this snippit to the relevent settings.json: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 &amp;#34;gopls&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;buildFlags&amp;#34;: [ &amp;#34;-tags=wireinject&amp;#34; ], &amp;#34;experimentalWorkspaceModule&amp;#34;: true }, } Tomorow&amp;rsquo;s Tasks</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/may-23rd-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/may-23rd-2022/</guid><description> Notes For {{date:dddd, MMMM Do YYYY}} This is a great read, needs to be finished howeer #business, #software #development https://sharedphysics.com/everything-is-important/#the-problem</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/october-18th-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/october-18th-2021/</guid><description>Notes For Monday, October 18th 2021 #TuringComplete Found an early access game (Written in #GoDot) Which allows you to build computers starting at the Logic Gate level, building into a computer and finally creating an assembly language for the machine you create. Still on the basic logic gates but have already learned something new and felt the excitment of putting it into practice -karnaugh-maps - A Method of working out the Sum Of Products Simplified form for Boolean Expressions.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/october-24th-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/october-24th-2021/</guid><description>Notes For Sunday, October 24th 2021 #Jetbrains #IDE #IdeaVim On a new install there are a lot of bell for actions that do no work, and since I have such a sloppy use of VIM it is really annoying. To disable: Basically, IdeaVIM reads your ~/.ideavimrc (~/.vimrc pre-v0.35) file and silently ignores any settings it does not understand. Of the bell-related settings, it does not understand :set noerrorbells, but it does understand :set visualbell.</description></item><item><title>April 4th, 2021</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-4th-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/notes/2021/april-4th-2021/</guid><description> Todo Spline Based Path Follower #Unreal Is this way the best way, or should it be handled in the movment component? InterpToMovementComponent as a good few ideas in there Today I learned (Notes) [Runge-Kutta][https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Runge%E2%80%93Kutta_methods] intergration, used in physics engines as it is more accurate than Euler intergration. #Maths #Simulation_Programming #Physics_Engies Curves And Splines. Third Order Polynomial functions that describe interplotated curves #Math #Game_Programming A Primer on Bézier Curves Really good free online book breaking down and describing Bézier Curves Splines An indepth Paper on Splines, how they work relation to other curves and coding examples (dropboxed under Books) Tomorow&amp;rsquo;s Tasks</description></item></channel></rss>