<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>projects on Shermans's Notes</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/tags/projects/</link><description>Recent content in projects on Shermans's Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://shermanrose.uk/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning Programming Through Competition</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/learning-programming-through-competition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/projects/learning-programming-through-competition/</guid><description>LPTC f, or short, was my final year university project. The project spec was to create an application to aid new learners in procedural based programming by having them compete for their code.
The application was written in Java and comprised of two parts.
The first was a simple text editor that could compile java byte-code at run-time. The second was a 2D arena based game where the compiled byte-code from multiple users was run.</description></item><item><title>Talk To Me - A 'Simple' Side Project</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/talk-to-me-a-simple-side-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/talk-to-me-a-simple-side-project/</guid><description>I have a 3 year old nephew, who loves comptuers, and why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t he? They are everywhere. I can remember the first time I saw anything like a computer. I have memories of playing the NES at the age of 2.
So as his very mature and responsible uncle, it is my duty to guide his journey in the devices that are shaping our entire lives. Since I have studied and practiced computing for more years than I like to think about, especially when considering how inept I am, I think it is important for him to know what to can do for and to him.</description></item><item><title>The Only Thing I Ever Wanted To Make</title><link>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/the-only-thing-i-ever-wanted-to-make/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shermanrose.uk/posts/2017/the-only-thing-i-ever-wanted-to-make/</guid><description>Yesterday I turned 28. For the last 13 years at least I have been very interested in computers and programming in general. I now could not imagine what I would be doing now if it were not for these devices that live in almost every aspect of my life.
Still I haven&amp;rsquo;t really done much with that, as far as I am concerned. I have made no great websites, services, products, or games.</description></item></channel></rss>